CHRISTOS TSOPELAS

Web Developer

Front-end developer with 8 years of experience mainly working with Javascript and React focusing on delivering high-quality user experiences and looking forward to contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DEEPSEA AI Athens, Greece (remote)

January 2024 - now

As part of the front-end team, we build and maintain 2 very sophisticated web apps according to client needs. Integration with back-end systems and handling large datasets require an efficient use of javascript. Applying best practices during development, optimizing component reusability. Additionally, the products leverage advanced AI technologies to provide intelligent solutions. The company's clients are in the shipping industry, demanding top-tier quality standards.

MIMACOM Stuttgart, Germany (remote)

October 2022 - October 2023

During this period I mainly worked on 2 projects.

Developed from scratch the new company's official website strictly following the sophisticated design mockups. Enriched the FLowable platform with custom components according to customer needs and ensuring integration with the platform's architecture.

Technologies used: NextJS, React, HTML5, SCSS Hosting & Deployment: Netlify, Github Actions

CMS: Contentful

Other technologies: Storybook, NX monorepo

Testing & CI: Jest, Cypress



Menelaou 25, Kallithea 17672 Athens Greece

Tel: +30 6934831454

Email: tsopelasat@gmail.com

Birth date: 11/08/1995

Nationality: Greek

In: LinkedIn

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL

FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES:

React, Angular, Vue, NodeJS, Material, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Redux, Jest, Cypress

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES: Git,

Agile, Jira, Confluence, Databases, Responsive design, Databases, Docker, Storybook, AEM, Contentful, BEM, Accessibility, SEO

AGILE ACTORS Athens, Greece

August 2017 - September 2022

During this period I had the opportunity to work for three different clients on a variety of projects. Below are more details:

National Bank of Greece

August 2017 - October 2018

Developed web services for the National Bank of Greece and integration with government services. Delivered scalable and user-friendly front-end interfaces. Conducted requirement analysis, design, and implementation of user interface CRM bank systems. Collaborated closely with other teams of Accenture and IBM.

Technologies used:

Front-end: Angularjs, Angular 6, HTML5, SCSS, Jest

- DT Wise

October 2018 - March 2019

Implemented and maintained the web application and collaborated as part of a small, agile team to maintain the application's APIs and databases. The project focused on data-driven energy efficiency, requiring the efficient handling and processing of large datasets to provide high quality statistics to the clients.

Technologies used:

Front-end: React, redux, saga, rxjs, HTML5, SCSS

Back-end: Node, express Database: Elasticsearch

Camelot (Illinois National Lottery)

March 2019 - September 2022

Being part of a 10-member team, I worked, under Agile methodologies, following 2-week sprints along with other talented engineers to maintain the web and mobile app and continuously implement new features as per client needs.

Working in such a big and well structured company in the gambling industry, provided me with valuable opportunities to improve my technical and soft skills across several areas. Technologies used:

Front-end: Vue, Scss, HTML, Freemarker

Mobile app: Cordova

CMS: AEM

Other technologies: Gitlab, Jenkins, Jest

LANGUAGES

Greek, English C2, German (Currently in the process of learning, A1 level)

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Various sports (Ski, Basketball, Hiking)

Interest in leading informatics and cutting-edge technology

PART TIME - FREELANCE PROJECTS

SWAPPCITY, ATHENS — full-stack

August 2017 - December 2019

Worked as full stack developer (a few hours a week) in a 4-member team developing a startup application. It was about a home swap travel application.

Technologies used: React, Redux, Nodejs, Express, Mysql, Socketio, Axios, rxjs

WIZEX, ATHENS — full-stack

March 2022 - August 2022

Worked as a front-end developer in a small team on a startup cryptocurrency platform. The project was discontinued due to legal limitations.

Technologies used: React Redux, Typescript

GREEK ARMY - Signals Corps

November 2020 - August 2021 (9 months)

While fulfilling my military obligations I refactored and converted into webapp an electron application for storing signal data and introduced an educational tool for the army employees to practise their knowledge. It was a full stack application that was build from scratch(duration: 3 months).

Technologies used: React, Nodejs, Express, Mysql.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Athens University of Economics and Business (2013 2021)
- Member of Agile Actors Academy, learning front-end technologies (2016-2017)

Online courses in: HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT ES6, SQL, REACT, REDUX, ANGULAR 2, Real-time Web with Node.js, NestJS (Udacity, CodeSchool, Egghead, Pluralsight, Freecodecamp, Udemy)

PERSONAL PROJECTS for educational purpose

- Creation of an Android application for senior citizens, not experienced with smartphones. (University Assignment)
- Creation of a 2D platform games(Chess, Hangman, tictactoe) using React, Nodejs, Express, socketio, mysql

CERTIFICATES

 NestJS Issued October 2023
https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-eb7b2d64-3103-4bec-b242-bde 432ad13af/